Javier Vivas

Davenport, FL, United States | (+1) 8633488877 | <u>javivasv@gmail.com</u> https://javivasv.com/ | https://github.com/javivasv | https://www.linkedin.com/in/javier-vivas-veliz/

ABOUT

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering with a strong background in frontend and fullstack development. Experienced in delivering high-performance web solutions with dedication and efficiency, quickly delivering quality work. Demonstrated ability to mentor junior developers. Enthusiastic about developing personal projects and continuously enhancing technical skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

JP Global Digital Miami, FL

Frontend Engineer

Nov 2021 – June 2024

- Leader of the frontend development team in a 3D interactive viewer web application
- Refactor of legacy authentication flows: sign up, sign in with two factor authentication, reset password
- Implemented a dashboard to provide easy access to the customers projects
- Developed an analytics page for customers to get insights of projects and their company
- Created a collapsible sidebar capable of containing thousands of elements at high performance and optimal resource usage requested by a major client as part of a contract negotiation
- · Mentor of junior frontend developers. Pair programming. Code reviews. Continuous feedback

BP Developments Caracas, Venezuela

Fullstack Developer

Jan 2021 – Oct 2021

- Responsible of creating a CRM web application
- Created authentication flows: sign up, sign in integrated with Google Authenticator, reset password
- Developed several modules: users, leads, contacts and communications (SMS, email and live chat)

Universidad Simón Bolívar Caracas, Venezuela

Software Developer

Jan 2020 – Dec 2020

Developed a web application to help the university community to get car rides from and to the campus

EDUCATION

Universidad Simón Bolívar

Caracas, Venezuela

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Certifications

- Programming for the Web with JavaScript
- CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript
- Single Page Web Applications with AngularJS
- Learn React
- React Testing Library with Jest / Vitest

edX – University of Pennsylvania edX – Harvard University

Coursera – Johns Hopkins University

Codecademy

Udemy

SKILLS

Technical skills

TypeScript, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, VueJS, Vuex, Vuetify, Material UI, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Jest, Vite, Vitest, AngularJS, Python, Django, Java, C#, ASP.NET, Websockets, Git, Jira, Azure, Heroku, Firebase, MongoDB Atlas

Languages

English, Spanish